#### **Andrew Milner**

Montreal, QC 514-575-4176 milnera92@gmail.com

andrewmilner.ca | github.com/milnera92 | linkedin.com/in/milnera

# **SUMMARY**

Highly motivated and enthusiastic Junior Software Developer with experience in the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js) and a strong understanding of the web development process. Proven ability to learn quickly and adapt to new technologies. Strong background in tech support, software development, and team management. Graduate of Concordia University's Full Stack Web Development program.

## **SKILLS**

- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, HTML
- Libraries and Frameworks: React.js, Express.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Axios
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL
- Web Development: REST APIs, JSON, DOM Manipulation, Dev Tools / Debugging
- **Development tools:** Git, Linux, CLI / Bash, API Clients (Postman, Insomnia)
- Deployment and Hosting: DNS, Vercel/Heroku, Docker, CI/CD

#### PROJECTS

#### **Encore** - encore-project.onrender.com

Dec 2022 - Jan 2023

- Full stack MERN app for displaying concert setlists and videos from the crowd
- Utilized Node.js and Express.js for the backend; consumed music APIs and gathered live setlist data, Map APIs for location, etc.
- Utilized REST APIs to update information in real-time, displaying setlist songs, YouTube videos of the show, and location
- Incorporated Autho for user login, providing the ability to save favorite setlists in a MongoDB database
- Styled using Styled Components, demonstrating an understanding of CSS fundamentals

### NordTech - nordtech-project.onrender.com

Nov 2022

- Utilized Agile methodology and Scrum to build a full-stack e-commerce store
- Constructed the backend using Node.js and Express.js, contributed to frontend using React
- Wrote custom APIs to query MongoDB and pull inventory information

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Concordia University**

Dec 2022

Diploma in Full Stack Web Development

#### **Nova Scotia Community College**

June 2016

Diploma in Information Technology

#### Saint Mary's University

June 2014

Bachelor of Commerce

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **EVO Payments**

Feb 2021 - May 2022

Manager, Warranty & Tier 2 Tech Support

- Designed an app to track software licenses, saving over \$100,000 per month in tracking & terminating unused licenses. Written using SQL, VBA and Powershell scripting in collaboration with Database Management Team in Poland
- Reduced warranty replacement turn-around time from 6 days to 48 hours within the first months of starting the position
- Reduced consistent warranty backlog of ~150 units per day to zero backlogged units per day on average
- Basic VBA coding used to automate some tasks in Excel

#### MindGeek

Aug 2020 - Jan 2021

Tech Support for Online Game

- Performed basic CRUD actions with a GUI such as resetting passwords, editing player currency, changing names, and editing player stats and inventory
- Verified bug reports from users and helped recover stolen/hacked accounts
- Strong knowledge of payment processing back-end to locate fraudulent charges •
- Use of multiple CMS platforms for the multitude of games supported

SuWu

April 2019- Feb 2020

Executive Sous-Chef

Managed team of 8 line cooks in a restaurant for evening service 6 days a week. Responsible for inventory, ordering, sales tracking, staff training, catering events, and new menu development. Worked closely with local media & influencers

#### **Nuvei Technologies**

Feb 2018 - March 2019

E-Commerce & POS Tech Support

- Assisted business owners with customer service and tech support inquiries related to their card reader, POS, and e-commerce
- Tested the latest software and hardware in the card processing industry before widespread launch
- Trained in the company's first wave of e-commerce integration support, assisted new e-commerce merchants as an ambassador for the new service